Who's the black private dick that's
a sex machine to all the chicks.
Shaft.
You damn right.
Who is the man that would risk
his neck for his brother man.
Shaft.
Can ya dig it.
Who's the cat
that won't cop out.
When there's danger all about.
Shaft.
Right on.
They say this cat shaft
is a bad mother...
Shut your mouth.
- I'm talkin' about shaft.
- Then we can dig it.
He's a complicated man.
But no one understands him
but his woman
John shaft.
Hey, what's up?
Looking good.
Looks like the kid got clocked with that.
He gonna make it?
Got his head stove in pretty good.
- Witnesses?
- Nope.
- He come from in there?
- He's dressed like it.
You let anybody leave?
- I know the job.
- Hey, I'm just doing mine.
Excuse me. Excuse me.
Was there anything peculiar?
Any commotions?
Did you see...?
All right? You just call her
and say what I told you to say.
Hang up the phone.
You don't worry about my father.
You worry about me.
I'm not gonna argue...
- What?
- How did you get that blood on yourself?
Blood. What blood?
I'm gonna ask you again.
If you give me attitude this time...
I'm gonna drag you out of here
by your hair.
How did you get that blood on yourself?
It was like...
He started it...
And I finished it.
Look, I was razzing the guy.
He couldn't take a joke.
So you cracked his head open.
- Hey, I can dig it.
- He left all pissed off.
I followed him out to apologize.
Next thing I know,
he's coming at me with a silver bat.
I was defending myself.
Anybody see you?
No, officer. It was just
me and him out there.
- Do you know who my father is?
- No. Do you?
- Take him out.
- Let's go.
What's your name?
- Diane palmieri.
- What'd you see, Diane?
Nothing.
So why you point that guy out to me
when I came in?
I didn't.
- What's that?
- What?
- What did you see, Diane?
- Nothing, I swear. I...
It's a zoo in here. And if I'm working,
how can I see anything?
Detective.
We have a potential witness
you should see.
I'll be back in a minute.
Keep her company, okay?
He did it. That racist bastard.
That's the one that did it.
How do you know? Did you see it?
No. He was sitting over there...
And he was hassling trey from
the minute we all walked in the door.
Right this way. This table over here.
Yo!
Excuse me, sir. Yo!
- What's up, man?
- They don't serve no malt liquor here.
No malt liquor, all right?
No. All right?
- All right.
- Okay.
- What the hell's your problem?
- Let's go. I wanna go.
- No. No, we're fine. We're fine, okay?
- So embarrassing.
Don't even worry about it.
All right. Have a seat over here.
- What did your friend trey do?
- Nothing.
He tried to ignore the guy,
but the bastard just wouldn't let up.
No 40s, no chronic.
And no... no indo, all right?
Hey. Hey, dog, is you deaf?
- Holler back!
- What? What an asshole.
You got that, Tupac? All right?
- And then what happened?
- Trey turned the tables on the guy.
What are you doing?
He took one of these
white napkins and a knife...
And he poked holes in it.
Then he walked over
to where the guy was sitting.
I think you dropped this.
And he dropped it on his head.
Bull's-eye.
And everybody laughed.
Take that, chump!
I guess that little prick was pissed.
He was embarrassed
that all his friends laughed at him.
Thank you. You can go
and check on your friend now.
- Getting a low pulse.
- We gotta move.
- We're losing him.
- Let's get rolling.
Tell me he is not the primary on this.
It's his catch, lieu.
Walter wade, Jr.
You big Walter wade's son?
- Yes, I am.
- The real estate developer?
Correct.
- Daddy's a big man?
- Big man.
Big man.
The waitress. She saw it?
So, what you do, motherfucker?
Threaten her?
She had to go to the John.
What the...?
- Where'd she go?
- She left.
Shit!
When we get him on board,
I'm gonna intubate.
Let's get that defib ready, guys.
He's starting to seize.
- He's having a seizure.
- I think he's dying.
- Homeboy's got rhythm?
- What?
Damn it.
Was it something I said?
I think my nose is broke.
- I'll clear his airway.
- Excuse me.
- He broke my nose.
- He's going fast.
- There's no air exchange.
- Come on.
Let's get this thing open.
I can't even get a pulse right now.
- Clamp an airway!
- There is chaos on the scene...
Damn, we're losing him!
- Son of a bitch!
- Trey!
I've been waiting for this all year.
You are gone from this precinct.
Gone? For what?
For that?
His roots in the community
couldn't go deeper.
He has no criminal record.
Your honor, the charge is homicide.
Not having done it before
is not an excuse.
Bail is set at $200,000.
That don't mean shit!
You're a killer, man!
Fuck you!
Can I get a statement from you?
- Shaft.
- It's Walter wade.
Thanks for breaking my nose that night.
My lawyer says that's why I got bail...
And that's precisely why
I'm skiing in Switzerland right now.
See you when I see you, slick.
Oh, come on, man. You suck.
- John shaft.
- Carmen vasquez. Welcome to narcotics.
- Jimmy groves.
- Jack roselli.
You transfer in from the 35?
Yeah. You John shaft?
- Heard you quit.
- Not yet.
Luger, hurry the fuck up, man.
Come on, you bitch bastard.
Come on, you Billy Bob motherfucker.
Open the goddamn door.
Let's go. Open the fucking door.
That's three happy meals or four?
- That's four. And hurry up.
- All right.
Freeze, motherfuckers! Don't move!
Move your fucking ass out of the way!
Police!
Freeze, goddamn it!
Everybody on the fucking ground!
Everybody freeze!
Grab that motherfucker!
Down on the floor! Now!
Somebody turn that fucking music off!
Get down on your fucking knees.
All right...
- Put your hands behind your back.
- Shaft, I got one.
Now you can't speak no fucking English.
I bet you can say "kilo," can't you?
- Hey! Hey, goddamn it! Hey!
- Come here! Come here!
Don't make me chase you!
You're gonna piss me off!
Stop, goddamn it! Stop!
I told you to stop, damn it!
Throw something else!
Disperse, motherfuckers! Disperse now!
Come on! Come on!
Watch your backs, ladies!
I'm gonna fuck you up for making me run!
You got me, papa.
Peace, motherfucker.
April fool, motherfucker.
I told you not to make me run, didn't I?
This shit's too tight, yo!
Sit in this car and think about
this ass-whooping you're gonna get.
It's gonna be a long ride to the precinct.
Paraphernalia. Nothing.
- Let me call my wife.
- Shut up, cornbread.
- Let me call my girlfriend.
- I said shut the fuck up.
Easy with the braids, man.
What you got
against black men anyway?
Supposed to be like a factory up there.
Must've gotten a heads-up from someone.
My kid's got more
indictable shit under his bed.
These scales 'll get revolved
before we clock out tonight.
- Look at him.
- Who's that?
Peoples Hernandez.
He's the neighborhood alligator.
It's all his play up here.
He's got about a half dozen apartments.
Keeps changing his shit on us
like it's a shell game.
You enjoying the show?
Yo, sprig, let me see the ball.
Fuck. John, don't do it. Come on.
John, come on. No!
Son of a bitch.
- Good shot.
- Peoples Hernandez, come on down!
Motherfuck.
Yes!
Shaft. You pissed him off
now. Here come the troops.
This is Egyptian cotton, motherfuck.
Two-twenty thread. This is like half
your shitty-assed paycheck, okay?
Step off, peoples.
You wouldn't know Egyptian cotton
if pharaoh himself sent it to you...
You knock-off wearing motherfucker.
- You best sleep in that vest.
- Oh, there you go, papi.
You're under arrest
for assaulting an officer.
Stay, Lucifer.
This is the only way you can touch me.
You're one pathetic Kentucky-fried nigga.
I got some chicken wing for you.
What have we got here?
Concealed weapon.
- The iceman goeth.
- Goeth for a long time.
Come on...
Step up
on the hop, folks. Let's go.
Come on. Let's go.
- Peoples. Peoples.
- Can I get my shoes shined?
Yeah, you sure can.
Home sweet home?
- Stay still, please.
- Yo, shaft.
I'm gonna put so many lawyers
on your ass...
You're gonna think
they opened a branch office up there.
Lawyers? Lawyers are for punetas.
- I thought you were gonna smoke me.
- I smoke camels.
It's not my size.
Yo, when the van comes
for these assholes...
This one gets the busted seat belt.
What the hell's he doing here?
Tell me it's something good.
Tell me it ain't one of your dick-arounds.
No. Honest to God, lieu.
I was in fear for my life.
- Yeah, yeah. I know the routine.
- Will you shut the fuck up, cornbread?
Yo, luger, what's up with the "cornbread"?
Your problem is what?
Nazis with badges. That's my problem.
Nazis?
You gotta lighten up, shaft.
I talk like this all the time.
I see your point.
Maybe I should take an ethnic-sensitivity
workshop? Fuck you.
Maybe I should workshop my foot
up your ass. How about that?
How about you pick a color, black or Blue?
- Hey, fuck you, luger.
- How about I make you both, luger?
- Take it easy.
- Anytime, anywhere.
Nothing between us but
air and opportunity.
Anytime, anywhere, shaft.
- Come on, motherfucker. Come on!
- Go, go, go!
Yo, shaft,
I like the way you handled that, brah.
Shut the fuck up!
Yo, shaft, you got a call.
Guy says it's urgent.
I think it's the clinic. I believe
the test results may have come back.
Today we find out if I'm your daddy
or the German Shepherd.
Pretty good.
Well, how good is good?
You're kidding me.
Red, if this is another one of your...
Solid info?
One hundred percent solid?
No shit.
Where?
All right. I got it. All right. Thanks.
Gotcha.
- What's up?
- Old business.
- You need backup?
- No, I got it.
- Rasaan.
- What?
- I'm calling in a favor, son.
- Favor, my ass, motherfucker.
You ain't got no favors
left with me, dog.
Them shits is through.
You done ran all your shits out, baby.
- Look, nigga, don't argue. Just do it.
- All right, dog.
What, rasaan? What happened?
I gotta do a favor
for my man real quick.
How you doing?
Let's get going.
How you doing, Richie rich?
Remember me?
Refresh my memory.
Put them on.
Yeah, what's the dilli? Where we off to?
- Fifteenth precinct.
- Okay, dog.
Hey, yo,
that's my dog shaft back there.
You know what I mean, that's my man.
Word up. You all right?
Cold, chilly?
You want a jacket or something?
I bet you thought I was sneaking back in.
Crown heights'. Bed-stuy!
Yeah! Bed-stuy!
I'm innocent.
You look depressed, shaft. You depressed?
Back away from the car.
Fuck with the bull...
You get the horns!
Yeah, shaft! Go on, baby! Yeah!
You the man, shaft! You the man!
Yeah, you the man! You the man, shaft!
You know, bro, I'll be out in an hour.
I don't think so, running man.
You see, the van to central processing
left about five minutes ago...
And there won't be another one
for hours and hours.
By the time you get downtown,
we're talking overnight in the tombs...
And they definitely
won't arraign your ass before morning.
It's a shame we didn't get here
a little sooner.
You look depressed, Walter.
You depressed?
Yo, peops, you still here?
- The seat belt on the van was busted.
- Oh, damn.
It's called habeas corpus, motherfucker.
That mean "due process,"
for the illiterate.
It's called, "you wanted
to play games with me," peoples.
I know a shitload of games.
You boys play nice.
Teflon don, nigga! Teflon!
Bitch.
Hey, blanqui, what he get you for?
Income tax evasion?
Fuck you.
Damn!
- What's happening?
- What's up, big boy?
Same old, same old.
Congratulations, man. You was on TV.
Let me get your autograph. You a star.
Mr. p., how you be?
Fine, fine.
- Who's winning?
- Who do you think?
- Hey.
- Congratulations, baby.
Lucky man.
Alice, Alice, ease up on my nephew.
Or that boy's gonna poke
a hole in something.
Uncle j! Hey.
Mr. big-time private eye.
Hey, I earned my pay today.
Well, you did bring him in.
There's no denying that.
- But what?
- What?
But what?
Come on, come on. Spit it out.
Nothing, nothing.
Listen, so when you gonna
come on board with me, my man?
- Soon.
- Soon?
You're always saying that.
Got a fucking nigga locked up!
Fuck, nigga! What's wrong with you?
You better watch your back!
- We shouldn't fucking be here, man!
- We got busted, man!
- The same bust!
- You making too much money!
Give me your shoes.
They wouldn't fit you.
Oh, shit!
I only ask once.
You want my shoes?
For two years now,
I've been meaning to ask you.
When you dress like this,
where exactly do you strap your piece?
You mean you forgot already?
Well, you know it was
way back in the day.
Oh, yeah. Maybe you should ask lamont.
Why I gotta ask lamont?
I'm standing right here.
- Hey! Hey!
- Damn, why you always up on my woman?
This is the type of
shit get a fucker killed.
He's just playing.
- Playing, my ass.
- I was asking a legitimate-ass question.
Why is it every time you see me talking
to her, you roll up on me like this?
- You feeling insecure?
- Lamont, he's just kidding.
I ain't studying this bullshit.
We can settle this right the fuck now!
- Back up off the motherfucking Armani.
- Fuck you and your Armani!
Surprise!
We got you, baby.
We got you. Surprise, baby.
We got you this time.
All right.
Do you want a smoke?
Don't smoke. Thanks.
My name is peoples.
You know why they call me that?
Because you always takes care
of your peoples?
Yeah, actually, more or less.
You play golf?
- Not for a while.
- Golf is phat.
Tiger wood. Tiger wood.
I like him.
You got a boat?
I had one.
What kind of boat you had?
- A Boston whaler.
- Boston whaler.
You been around the world, right?
- Yeah.
- You know something?
I got money longer than train smoke.
I ain't never been on airplane once
my whole goddamn life.
Let me ask you something.
The...
Five family, five borough, one love.
Okay.
You an interesting motherfuck.
You got like a business card or something?
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
Don't kiss me, motherfucker.
- All right.
- Night.
- Good night.
- Later, dog.
Back in custody tonight
after a two-year flight from justice.
Wade, seen here after
his arraignment in 1998...
Was rearrested by
detective John shaft...
As he flew into Westchester
county airport tonight.
I don't get it.
Why the fuck did he come back?
If it was me, I'd never come back.
Yeah, see, if there ever
was a "but what?" That'd be it.
Come to justice, that kid's old man's
got enough juice here...
To slip his thumb on the scale
and nobody 'll say nothing.
Ain't no fucking way he walks from this.
- No way.
- Really?
Let's roll.
- Good night.
- Night, all.
Such a cynical motherfucker.
You wanna come home with me tonight?
- It's been a while.
- So, what is it this time?
You just wanna be held,
or you want the ID?
What you think it is?
I want the ID, baby.
And then I wanna be held.
- That's all right with you?
- You know me.
It's my duty to please that Booty.
Finish up. Let's go.
Kearney, how's retirement?
Catfish are jumping.
Yeah, I heard you bought a big house
out in Nassau county.
Four-bedroom colonial,
right on the water.
Let me ask you something.
How does a third-rate, pencil-pushing,
apple-stealing, dick-head like you...
Afford a four-bedroom colonial
in Nassau motherfucking county?
How much they pay you, kearney?
After working a job uptown for 28 years...
You know what I like best
about where I live?
How do I say this?
It's a restricted community.
Your honor, my client did not fly home
5,000 Miles to jump bail.
- You mean jump bail again.
- No doubt.
He was in the wind for two years, judge.
And if he decides to take off again,
the mood of the people in this city...
Talk about the people!
We can't risk the possibility...
Of waiting another two years,
another two months, two days, two hours.
The district attorney's office
is ardently opposed to any kind of bail.
- How about no bail?
- Remove that man.
- Get him out of here.
- How about no bail?
Hey, back up, son! Back up, son!
Hey, son.
Hey, yo, you gonna get your ass twisted.
You better get off me! Get off me!
Your point is well taken, Mr. Torres.
The defendant is hereby ordered
to surrender his passport to this court.
However, I believe that young Mr. wade...
Is sincere in his desire
to deal with whatever form of judgment...
This room deems necessary to deliver.
- Bail is set at one million dollars.
- What?
- No!
- Your honor...
My client is prepared to post bail.
Oh, no!
Goddamn.
- What the fuck is wrong with you?
- I'm out. I'm done.
What, are you nuts? Think.
- Come on, John. This is wack.
- Fuck the job!
- I'll get him my own goddamn way.
- Insane!
- Hey, hey! Hey!
- All right, I'm cool. I'm cool.
I quit.
"Shaft".
I remember when I took that job...
Thinking I could fight the good fight
from the inside...
And you telling me about all the problems.
That color thing.
"Too black for the uniform,
too Blue for the brothers."
About how justice
gets tangled up in red tape...
Or just bought off by the green.
You were right.
Fuck that job. Fuck the badge.
I'll get that silver-spoon motherfucker
and I'm gonna get him my own way.
No lawyers, no politics,
no rules, no regulations.
- No pension.
- What?
You're too hot, man.
You gotta step off a bit.
- Let me put my people on him.
- No. Hell no.
- His ass is mine.
- Hey, what's the difference?
Got is got.
His ass...
Is mine.
I believe we're in pretty
good shape on this.
What about the waitress?
Paul, talk to him. Thank you.
The truth is, Walter, we can't find her.
This guy is great.
You know why we can't find her?
Because she doesn't want to be found.
Now, do you want to go back to Switzerland
while we try and track her down?
It could take a year, two, 10, maybe never.
Meanwhile, everything
and everyone else is in place.
- I don't believe this.
- Look.
Even if she does surface,
she is seriously damaged goods.
It's just a roll of the dice, kid.
- I'll roll my own damn dice.
- Now, Walter... Walter.
- Hello. How are you?
- Hello, my darling.
- How was your day?
- Fine.
So is that my mother's choker?
- Well...
- You gave her my mother's jewelry?
Well, let me... Walter. Walter.
Walter!
Hi, Ms. palmieri. Remember me?
Look, I really need to talk to Diane.
She don't live here.
She lives in the Bronx.
Yeah, I checked the last address I had.
Well, right now she's in Europe.
- Europe? Where in Europe?
- Spain.
- Spain? I love Spain.
- Maybe Italy.
I never know until I get the postcard.
What can I tell you?
Hey, okay.
Thanks.
I'll probably get fired for this,
but I thought you might need some help.
Terry. From metronome, right?
- Remember me?
- Yeah.
How did you find me?
Yeah.
I'm free on Monday nights...
Tuesday nights
and every other Wednesday.
Read my mind. Why am I here?
- You're looking for Diane?
- Got it.
- What's in it for me?
- What you need?
Fuck that bitch!
Look down the corner.
See that little nigga,
the one with the red hat?
That's Malik, okay?
Now, my son Tony, he's a real good boy.
A good student.
But he's 12, and I caught him twice
last week running errands for Malik.
I need for that to stop.
Can you handle that?
Everybody on fucking drugs!
Nothing but money, man!
That's Monday, Tuesday
and every other Wednesday.
- Right?
- You got it, baby.
Fucking haves and the should not haves,
motherfucker.
Who the fuck is to say
I shouldn't have shit?
Anybody looking to maintain
their employment with the N.Y.P.D...
It might be in their best interest
to leave now.
Diamonds and pearls
I mean, whoa.
Should've seen the lights shine, nigga
whoa.
Yo!
Down! Down! Down! Down! Down!
Man, leave him alone, man!
- What's my name?
- What?
- I don't know.
- John shaft!
- What?
- John shaft! Say it!
- John shaft.
There's a kid lives up the block
about 12 years old named Tony.
- You know him?
- Yeah.
Wrong answer! There's a kid lives down
the block about 12 years old named Tony.
- Do you know him?
- No, I don't know that kid.
- Stay!
- I don't know that nigga, not no more.
- Quit pointing the gun!
- This kid you don't know.
You see him coming, you run
for your motherfucking life. You got that?
- Do you ever wanna see me again?
- No.
- No!
- What's my name?
- I forgot.
- John shaft. John shaft.
John shaft, yo.
Cleveland is.
Memphis and little rock, my brothers is
whoa.
My New York peoples, they down like
You ever wanna see me...?
You answered that?
My bad.
What? What?
We're not done, hold me down like
whoa.
My fam too deep, hold me down like
The whole j.U., hold me down like
whoa.
The whole eastside, hold me down like
- What the fuck's all that?
- Get the fuck off me!
- Give that back to me, man.
- It worked out great.
Yeah. Okay.
Hey, hey, hey, guys. Break it up.
You're fighting over a bit of rubber?
- He started it.
- No, you always start it.
Here. Jump for it, okay? And behave.
Is that the best you can do? Come on!
You can't handle this!
- Get out of the way. Get out of the way.
- Hey, stop!
Get the fuck out of the road!
What are you fucking doing,
you crackhead?
Leon, the minute she shows up,
you call me, right?
Yeah. All right.
How you gonna get me
into the police academy...
With you chucking your job like that?
- Who lost your rap sheet for you?
- You.
- Who got you that tryout with the jets?
- Who got you that gig at the club?
- You.
- Who delivers 10 times out of 10?
- All right, dog. You got it. You.
All right. So shut the fuck up
and call me when she shows.
Why the hell you wanna be a cop...?
Forget I asked. Got milk?
Yeah, I got some milk. You want some milk?
I got a whole bunch of milk.
Mira, no, I am telling you...
Jeter hit one home run,
two doubles and he walk once.
He walk once.
You dressing down
to blend in or something?
You look like a fucking duck hunter.
I need someone located.
Located? What you mean, found?
Located and then what?
That's gonna cost you.
- What am I, a pawnbroker?
- I had it all appraised.
It'll cash out to about 40,000.
- Stole?
- Inherited.
Inherited?
Forty thousand?
Yo, peoples, it's him.
Has been the subject
of fierce racial demonstration...
- That's you.
- The man's fucking famous.
Hundreds of people
were outside the courthouse Monday...
Protesting the judge's decision
to grant bail.
The case continues to arouse
fierce passions in this city.
The trial is scheduled to begin
in two weeks.
We are, of course,
following this case very closely...
To bring you the latest developments.
Flaco, flaco, flaco,
we got Hollywood right here in the house.
I gotta tell you something.
In this neighborhood,
I am the motherfucking king snake.
I do like this on 181,
three people die on riverside.
But the thing of it is, you know...
I go downtown, right,
to take a girl out, show her the sights.
I walk into a restaurant,
my stomach's in a knot...
My teeth is clenched,
my hands is in fists.
I don't fit in down there.
People look at me, size me up.
So, like, 10 minutes into it,
I can't wait to come back home.
- I'm like a prisoner, you know?
- Okay.
But youuu...
See, I would kill to be you.
Go where you go. Do what you do.
So this is what I propose.
Okay, the jewelry and shit,
go hock the flash, bring me the cash.
I'm not gonna not take it.
But what I really want?
I want you
to start taking me downtown with you.
I want you to start taking me
wherever you go.
You mean, like, hang out together?
"Hang out." That's good.
Take you to, what, lutece,
the Harvard club?
- What the hell are you talking about?
- No, no, no.
When I say "me"...
"Me" is this.
Hi.
I want you to front for me, be my face.
Get me some upscale customers.
I would like that very much.
You do that for me,
you get me into your world...
I do that bitch for you. Word is bond.
Man, you're doing a little bit
too much of your own product.
- What?
- Look, it's 40,000.
I thought it was gonna be more,
but that's what it is.
I mean, if it's really important to you...
You can tell everybody
you got a rich white boy on a rope.
I really don't care. But entre nous?
No fucking way.
What's up, peoples? Let me keep this.
You know...
You took a big risk
coming here all by yourself.
Did I?
- Yo, peoples, can I keep this?
- No.
- Forty thousand?
- That's what I said.
But this other thing, you can't do for me?
- Not on your life.
- Not on my life?
Peoples, let me live.
Let me keep that ice.
No.
The man gonna need it
to raise some money.
You drive a hard bargain, blanquito.
Where the fuck did he go?
Hey!
What is wrong with you,
sneaking around behind me like that?
You wanna die?
- Hey. Come on.
- Get in the car.
He had this...
Money belt stuffed with rocks.
Peoples tell him to cash it in and...
Done deal.
You talking about Walter wade,
the white boy, right?
From the television.
I tell you, man,
they're gonna kill that white girl.
What's up?
Just getting to know the lay of the land.
- How you doing?
- Yeah, I'm having a conversation here.
The courthouse, man,
that was some rough shit.
Right, right. Sure you're right.
- You sure you're all right?
- Yeah, I'm cool.
Hey, shaft, I heard you quit LA policia.
So I don't think it's right
I still gotta do this shit any more.
Okay, okay. Okay, shaft, okay.
This guy comes in here...
He's got his drawers
stuffed with jewelry and he asks me:
"Can you locate somebody?"
And I say yeah, because
he's kind of like a celebrity, you know.
You don't want to say no.
I mean, he's coming to me,
it's all flattering and shit.
But the truth of it is, finding people,
that's not really my, as they say, forte.
So this is what I propose.
You detectives and shit, right?
You detect.
So why don't I subcontract to you?
The guy says the shit'll
cash out to about 20 gs.
He's gonna bring it by tonight.
With you I split it down the middle, 50-50.
Easiest money you'll ever make.
You take half, I take half.
Ten large?
Ten thousand.
Alls you gotta do is
tell me where she's at.
- Then what happens?
- Easiest money you'll ever make.
You wanna tell him about tattoo?
Can I talk to you for a moment?
What?
- Wonder what the market did today.
- How the fuck should I know?
- All the white boys.
- Get the fuck out of here!
No, no, no black people.
I heard you need a job. But this?
You know when guys like you
go down for good?
When they get aspirations.
When they try and rise
above their station.
Now, this contract killing thing
you got with Walter Jr.
Do yourself a favor.
You're a two-bit, three-block dope dealer.
Stick to what you know.
Stick to what I know? Stick to what I know?
Fuck you, motherfucker. I'm a star.
You ain't shit.
You ain't even a fucking pig no more.
Do you think that makes me
less dangerous or more dangerous?
Now, I see you somewhere
I think you don't belong...
I will kill you.
Look.
I respect you. I like you.
That why you always wanna fuck me?
Why you flinch?
- Ms. palmieri.
- Wait here.
Motherfuckers!
She didn't see nothing,
and she ain't gonna testify.
- You stay the fuck away from my sister!
- No guns! Take it easy!
She's your sister?
Well, if your sister didn't see anything,
why's she running so hard?
- Just leave her be.
- Wade threaten her again?
- Don't move.
- This is fucking bullshit!
If he threatened her,
I can take care of that.
- Just leave her be.
- Frankie.
- Mikey.
- Ma, go back in the house.
- We just wanna talk to her.
- Yeah, sure, with those guns. Get lost.
What do you think?
- They shot a blank.
- Nothing, right?
Nada.
Come on, shaft. Lead us to that waitress.
I think we're being tailed.
Roselli and groves.
- They're following us?
- They saw me with tattoo last night.
Now peoples is probably
paying them to find Diane.
So, yeah, they're following us.
First Walter, peoples.
Now these two.
They like to fuck with people?
I guess I'm gonna have to show them
what fucking with people's all about.
47th and fifth.
- What you staring at, bitch?
- Punk-ass!
You better keep stepping, motherfucker.
Fucking white boy.
Freeze, mofo,
before I bust a cap in your dome!
Fuck!
- How'd I sound?
- How'd you sound?
"Freeze, mofo,
before I bust a cap in your dome."
Oh, pure notorious p.L.G.
Thank you, man.
That means a lot coming from you.
- How much we get?
- Hang on, hang on.
You are so damn controlling.
Forty-two thousand. That's a lot of count
for a simple murder around here.
I know cats that'd take out
a whole zip code for that kind of cheese.
No doubt.
Anyways, it's a one-time favor, okay?
I owe you one.
Hey, you still a motherfucking cracker.
You know that, right?
Fuck you, too, cornbread.
I'm out.
"Peoples".
Well, I gotta tell you...
The wheels are already set in motion.
You know what I'm saying?
You can't just turn off the dogs of war.
Look, I got fucking mugged.
- I have no money.
- I hear you, I hear you, I hear you.
Well, I guess you just
got to earn it back.
Ounces are 1,000.
Eight-ball's 200. A gram's 80.
It's all prebagged.
And I tell you like I tell all my boys, if
you cut it any more than it already is...
You can say goodbye
to repeat customers.
You gotta be shitting me.
You keep coming back,
re-up with me nine or 10 times...
We should be even-Steven
in about six, eight months.
Is this a fucking joke?
To keep in touch.
- Hello?
- Mom, you called me?
I just want to tell you
those detectives came around.
- I'm not testifying!
- I know. I know.
I'm not a bad person. I'm not.
I know you're not.
- I won't testify!
- Baby.
Please, mom, just keep them away from me.
Diane?
718-555-2473.
I need a number check.
Comes up Tony decarlo,
114 cromwell street, marine park.
And hey, tell shaft get that bastard.
He's probably getting
one of those simonize jobs.
Let's play games.
- How you doing, partner?
- You ready, Leon?
Let's roll.
Come on, shaft. Lead us to the prize, baby.
Bro, I gotta pee.
He's sitting right over there.
He'll lead you right to the girl.
- You got our money?
- Oh, yeah.
- That boy, the celebrity, he got mugged.
- He what?
Yeah, he showed up at my house all,
like, "no tengo dinero, boss."
- Do I look like a fucking fool to you?
- I don't know.
- Yo, where's our money?
- I just told you he got mugged.
I mean, that's like an act of God,
you know.
- Where is our fucking money?
- He got mugged. Ask him.
Dangerous times are here now.
You got to watch your back, too.
- You watch yours, too.
- New world order.
You got to be very careful.
Yo, yo, give me peoples, man.
Hello? Who the fuck is this? Hello?
Say exactly what I told you,
word for word.
I'll blow his motherfucking brains out.
- Take it easy. Just be ready.
- What?
"Rasaan".
Hey, yo, them two Jakes you fucking with?
They robbed the white boy
and they got the money under the seat.
They playing you, dude.
- Step out of the car, please.
- Excuse me?
Yo, yo, yo, what's up?
What's this about? What?
What? What?
Let's roll, soul.
Oh, shit.
I know what this is gonna sound like,
but we had no idea.
- You know what that's gonna sound like?
- Come on, easy.
- Shut up.
- If we thought of it...
Which we didn't, we would've
taken him out ourselves, okay?
We're none the less nice people here.
But that being said, we delivered.
You got your dough.
- Now give us our cut.
- Your cut?
I'll give you your cut,
you thieving motherfucker!
Give us our fucking money!
We'll kill you!
- Someone's gotta go! Let's all die!
- Hold it! Hold it! Peoples! Yo, peoples!
- I saw shaft. He drove off.
- What?
- Shaft?
Then who the fuck is that?
What?
He's playing us. Shaft is playing us.
- You got it, right?
- Yeah, I got it, baby.
Hello, can I speak to
Diane palmiri, please?
No, rasaan. Palmieri.
Palmieri! I said I got it, dude.
What the fuck you looking at me
like that for, anyway?
Hi. Good morning.
I'm from publisher's clearing house.
Is Diane palmiri home
at the moment?
I don't know who you're talking about.
Wait a second. I'm saying though...
Wait a second!
You got some dough coming!
- Go. Go, go, go.
- Wait a minute! I ain't bullshitting!
Wish this fool'd hurry up
so we could get the fuck out of here.
It's okay. It's okay!
- Leave me alone!
- Listen to me!
Mikey, get your brother
and get over here now.
Yo, shaft! Yo!
Shit. You motherfucker
bring me out here for this bullshit.
Be in there, man.
- What the fuck, brah, let me go.
- I said stay!
- Yo, shaft!
- Start the fucking car!
Come on! Come on!
No.
- Yo, get the broad in the fucking car!
- Get in the car! Open the door!
No! You killed my little brother!
You best kill me!
You best kill me, motherfucker!
- Get in the car.
- You best kill me, motherfucker!
You best kill me!
- Let my sister go!
- Diane! Diane!
- Get out of here, rasaan! Hurry up!
- Let her go!
- Diane!
- Fuck you, motherfucker.
- Calm down!
- I'll choke that motherfucker!
- She didn't see nothing!
- What the fuck are you doing to her?
- Go, goddamn it!
- You got me out here with no fucking...
Mikey!
You fucked him!
Fuck you!
- Damn it, you motherfucker, I'll...
- Mikey!
Mikey!
This is fucked.
You follow them.
- Peoples, at this point...
- Look at my little brother!
You follow them, you find out
where they go, and you call me.
I'll take it from there.
Don't worry about it, you puerco sucio.
Motherfucker, you owe me now,
Mr. big-time shaft.
I tell you, before we get up
in here, I'm gonna have to warn y'all.
I gave the cleaning lady a few years off.
You know, let her get her shit together.
Once I pick some of this shit up,
light some candles and incense...
- Everything 'll be just cool.
- Goddamn, rasaan.
- This is like a biohazard in here.
- You're welcome.
Why don't you sit down,
have a seat, relax.
I'm a bad man.
- You first. That's nasty.
- What? Sit down.
Go ahead. Sit down.
Man, this is some repugnant shit.
Fuck!
Wait a minute! What the fuck is...?
You come into my life, next thing I know
shaft put my little brother in a box.
- What?
- Snatched that bitch out from under me.
- Put my brother in a box.
- He what?
What you mean what? You can't hear me?
You got something in your ear?
No!
I come back later, put this in your ass.
You fucking...
Hey, Carmen, I got John shaft on the line.
Yeah, peoples.
Sixty-eight fifty norstrom Avenue...
Between prospect place and park place.
We'll sit tight in case he makes a move.
I'm a bad man.
There was no father there for me
hey, and...
Yo, ra's.
We would just to go without eatin'.
Hey, how you like me now?
You're a bad man.
Hey, yo, big man.
What are you doing over there?
Come on. Let's get going over there.
Yeah, real funny.
Let me use your phone.
I wanna check on my brother.
All right, paisan. Go
check on your fratello.
Look, it's just the two of us here.
You saw it, didn't you?
And it's like a big, flat stone
laying on your chest.
You gotta let go of it, Diane.
Trust me on this.
Just let it go.
I was on my break.
I went out front to have a cigarette.
I was out there about 10 minutes.
I see the black kid, trey, coming out.
He was pissed.
Talking to himself,
like, pacing and cursing.
He didn't see me.
Then, like...
A minute later the wade guy comes out.
He doesn't even break stride.
He snatches up this silver,
I don't know, pole.
And the trey kid turns to him,
and he saw him.
He saw it coming. Just bashes him.
The spray, you know.
Blood.
Then he sees me.
Wade.
I wanted to run. I just...
My legs wouldn't move.
And he comes over and pushes me.
Give me your wallet.
I didn't understand.
Diane palmieri.
You see that?
You want a taste of that?
You want a taste?
You're gonna go back inside,
you're gonna finish your shift.
Then you're gonna go home.
Somebody will call you later tonight.
Do you understand me?
I don't even remember going back inside.
I remember talking to you...
I remember ducking out
the back and going home...
And I got a call like he said I would.
Some guy.
Very smooth, very...
And the next day I just started running.
I been kind of running ever since.
Okay.
Now here's the good news.
You are about to stop running.
- This trial is gonna...
- You don't get it, do you?
I took money.
The man who called me that night,
he offered me $100,000 to get lost.
Half right then, and half after the
disposition of the case. And I said yes.
I took $50,000, and I disappeared.
See, I told myself, I
pointed him out to you.
I fingered that son of a bitch,
and I got him arrested.
And I told myself that was enough.
But obviously it wasn't.
I mean, obviously.
I'm so sorry.
These last two years...
They must've been hell on you.
What?
I could be trading
stocks on the Internet.
Yeah, I could be home
watching the Knicks.
Yeah.
Oh, shit!
- Could she know about us?
- How the fuck do I know?
- Jesus.
- She's coming this way.
Play it easy. Play it...
stay with me on this.
Yeah.
- How you doing?
- Hey.
- Hey. What are you guys doing here?
- Watching your back.
I just got here. My back?
Your back, shaft's back. You know.
Well, he never said
where he was gonna be.
The drums. You hear things.
Drums?
He picked a pretty tough
neighborhood to lay low in?
- You wearing your vest?
- No.
- Jesus Christ!
- Hey!
- Shit.
- Police business. Police business.
What the fuck you shooting at now, Jake?
Shooting your ass
if you don't get out of my face!
- Hey, fuck you!
- Step off, assholes. Get a life, girls.
- Hey, get these nuts, cops!
- Go piss in the bed, boy.
- What?
- Yeah, yeah, keep walking.
- Keep walking. Yeah.
- Fake-ass cops.
Oh, shit.
What next, maestro?
- We finish what we started.
- No shit.
- What the fuck I do with these keys?
- Rasaan!
- Hurry up. Come on.
- Be right there. Don't rush me.
- You ready?
- Yeah, let's go.
Come on, Diane. Let's go see the da.
Get out the window, now!
Oh, shit!
Out! Out! Go!
Motherfucker, you got my house fucked up!
- Go. Let's get them.
- Stay behind me. Come on!
Come on! Come on, Diane!
Go! Go!
They went out the window!
Hurry the fuck up!
Come on.
Oh, fuck, man!
Go to the car! Go to the car!
- Come on, go, go!
- This way. This way. This way.
Why?
My kids. You can't believe what
private schools are charging nowdays.
This is breaking my heart.
Shoot him.
It's giuliani time.
Styling.
Go!
Yo, shaft, get the fuck in the car!
I'm about to leave
all you motherfuckers, man!
- What the fuck y'all doing?
- Rasaan, shut the fuck up and drive!
Oh, shit! Fuck! Shit! Fucking...
Hold on, y'all!
Shoot his ass!
Oh, shit! The car!
Watch that shit!
You fucking up my car, you pussies!
Just drive, goddamn it! Drive!
We're busted!
Yeah! Shoot all their motherfucking asses!
Yeah! Yeah!
It's okay. It's okay, calm down. Calm down.
They can't fuck with us!
You know how I hold it behind the wheel.
They can't fuck with me.
Hey, shaft!
No more teflon don, yo.
No more mayimbe.
I'm a motherfucking dead man.
First to admit it.
Maybe you kill me, or the cops.
Maybe I kill myself. I don't know.
- What do you think?
- Look, this is between you and me.
- Let her go.
- You know, that's the funny thing, shaft.
I'm not your enemy. I'm peoples.
- They your enemy.
- Hey! Hey!
I ain't no your enemy. They your enemy.
So now you're doing
wade's dirty work?
You gonna shoot me, shaft?
- All I got is this. Let's go, man.
- Okay.
All right, I'm putting the gun down.
Mano-a-mano. Come on. Let's go.
Take your woman!
I'm not your enemy.
I'm peoples.
Come on, motherfucker. Come on.
You through?
It's okay.
Walter wade Jr...
The son of wealthy
real estate developer Walter wade...
Who fled the country
more than two years ago...
Has been out on bail
awaiting this day...
To try and convince a jury
of his innocence.
Hey, she passes through. Let her pass.
Come on through.
- Everybody else, back up, please.
- Hey.
This morning we got a whole new lineup.
Got a new judge, the da himself
is running the prosecution...
And we have an eyewitness.
Today we're gonna get our money's worth.
I know we will.
- Shaft, can we get a word?
- How you doing?
Mrs. Howard, do you
have a comment on the new prosecutor?
Hey-
- I'm scared to death.
- Hey, look, you're gonna be fine.
If you feel yourself tightening up...
- Just look for you.
- I'll be there.
Okay.
Jesus.
You don't even have to look at him.
- Okay?
- Okay.
Okay. Okay.
- I hope you die a slow death!
- Back off! Back off!
- Guilty!
- Back it off! Let's go!
No! No, don't!
Get down!
Let her go! Let her go!
Let her go! Let her go! Let her go!
You still determined to be a private eye?
- I think you're making a mistake.
- I don't.
- Why don't you come in with us?
- I like what I do.
Yeah, right.
- You detective shaft?
- Used to be.
I need to file me an assault charge
against my boyfriend.
People say I should talk to you.
This is detective vasquez. She's...
She's unavailable at the moment.
See that guy on the phone over there?
When he's done, he'll help you.
- They said I should talk to you.
- I don't work here anymore.
Just have a seat over there.
When he's done, he'll help you.
Write the asshole's name
and where I can find him.
- You can't do that.
- One for the road.
All right, why don't you
get that looked at?
I'll see what I can do.
- Now what?
- I guess I gotta pull this asshole's coat.
- Wanna back me up?
- Back you up?
Bye.
Good luck to you.
Damn jerk.
Yo, shaft, man, we gotta talk, dog.
What's the deal, son?
The deal is, my life is fucked, man.
You know what I mean? I ain't got no car.
I ain't got no business.
I can't eat.
You done came by the apartment
and shot up the whole fucking building.
- Landlady wanna put me in the street.
- Calm down, man. It ain't that bad.
- What?
- It ain't all that.
Fuck both of y'all then.
It's my motherfucking life
you talking about.
Rasaan, rasaan, shut up. Here.
What you giving me that for?
This is for me?
This is my shit?
That's why I love you, baby...
My motherfucker.
You always take care of me.
I love you for that, baby.
- Come on, let's roll. We got work to do.
- You call this work?
Yeah, cat.
Yo, say, shaft, I been thinking, yo.
Y'all should make me an associate...
In this detective game y'all got going
on over here, you know what I mean?
I wouldn't do
no hard-core detective work.
I wanna be one of them cats
who gets to take pictures...
Of the broads
cheating on their husbands.
I just wanna hold a camera, dog.
All you'll be holding
is the steering wheel.
Yeah, brother, yeah.
We off into the sunset, brother.